{
  "type": "k12_test",
  "tests": [
    {
      "title": "Show-and-Tell",
      "author": "",
      "passage": [
        "Marcus was not happy. His teacher, Ms. Page, had announced that they would do something different for show-and-tell that Friday.",
  "“I want you to bring in a book that you’ve never forgotten,” she said. “You’ll show us your favorite book, and tell us a little bit about it and why it matters to you.”",
  "Marcus was shy, but he usually liked show-and-tell, because he could bring something cool to school and talk about it without being the center of attention. His classmates were usually focused on whatever gadget he was describing. But a book wouldn’t protect Marcus from attention at all.",
  "",
  "At home that afternoon, he dropped into a chair and hardly spoke when his mother asked him about his day.",
  "“Why are you so grumpy?” she asked.",
  "He grunted, “No reason.”",
  "Marcus’s mother never put up with that sort of talk, so he finally told her about show-and-tell.",
  "",
  "“I see,” she said, looking thoughtful. After dinner, she handed Marcus a book. “This is your book for show-and-tell,” she said. It was one of their favorites, The Dot by Peter H. Reynolds. It’s about a girl who tells her art teacher that she can’t draw. The teacher tells her to put a dot on her paper; when she does, the teacher tells her to sign her name. Soon, her dot is framed and hanging in the classroom. That dot launches the girl’s love of art.",
  "",
  "After reading The Dot, Marcus finally worked up his nerve to try drawing a cartoon like the comic books he loved. Just like the girl in the story, once he started drawing, he couldn’t stop!",
  "“I know you’re not crazy about talking in front of people, but The Dot is easy to explain,” his mother said. “Then you can show them one of your original comic books.”",
  "“Show them something I drew?” Marcus said, horrified. “No way.”",
  "“Yes,” his mother answered. “All kids think comic books are cool, and yours are amazing.”",
  "",
  "Marcus didn’t have any better ideas, so the next morning he headed to school with The Dot and one of his comic books. When his turn came, Marcus raced through his summary of the book. Then he nervously explained that the story gave him the courage to try drawing his own comics. His stomach was in knots as he pulled his comic book out of his binder, hoping his classmates would like it.",
  "",
  "He passed around a comic about a superhero named Zen saving a school bus full of children from an army of giant ants.",
  "“Wow!”",
  "“Let me see it!”",
  "“Look at Zen’s suit—so cool!”",
  "Ms. Page clapped her hands. “Stop pushing and shoving. Marcus, thank you for sharing The Dot. It’s a great reminder that we all have creative talent if we have the courage to try. You’re obviously a very talented artist—given all this excitement, I’d say your comic book is a big hit!”",
  "",
  "Marcus headed home with a spring in his step, the compliments of his classmates echoing in his head."
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": "q1",
          "question": "Which word describes Marcus?",
          "choices": {
            "A": "curious",
            "B": "talkative",
            "C": "loving",
            "D": "shy"
          },
          "answer": "D"
        },
        {
          "id": "q2",
          "question": "What skill did Marcus begin using after reading The Dot?",
          "choices": {
            "A": "singing",
            "B": "drawing",
            "C": "painting",
            "D": "dancing"
          },
          "answer": "B"
        },
        {
          "id": "q3",
          "question": "How are Marcus and the girl in The Dot alike?",
          "choices": {
            "A": "They dislike doing homework.",
            "B": "They love art once they try it.",
            "C": "They have an interest in cool gadgets.",
            "D": "They like drawing comic book characters."
          },
          "answer": "B"
        },
        {
          "id": "q4",
          "question": "Which word describes Ms. Page in paragraph 24 of the selection?",
          "choices": {
            "A": "encouraging",
            "B": "surprised",
            "C": "anxious",
            "D": "curious"
          },
          "answer": "A"
        },
        {
          "id": "q5",
          "question": "How do Marcus’s feelings change during the selection?",
          "choices": {
            "A": "from nervous to shy",
            "B": "from excited to upset",
            "C": "from angry to surprised",
            "D": "from uneasy to pleased"
          },
          "answer": "D"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "title": "Adapted from “A Runaway Umbrella”",
      "author": "by Flora Louise Whitmore",
      "passage": [
  "There was a big umbrella with a pretty, twisted handle that belonged to Father, and he
carried it downtown on rainy days. There was a little brown-eyed girl, who was four
years old; that was Marjorie.",
"",
"There was a playful south wind that would be quiet for a long time and then come with a
quick gust and blow, oh, ever so hard and play all sorts of pranks on people.",
"",
"Then, there was a lady who sat on a porch not very far from Marjorie’s house. It was a
beautiful sunny day and Marjorie was going out in the front yard to play. As she went
through the hall, there by the hall tree*stood the big umbrella."
"",
"“Wouldn’t it be fun to take the umbrella and play rainy day?” she thought. So she
reached and picked it up.",
"",
"Through the door, across the porch and down onto the sidewalk she ran. She worked a
long while before she could get the umbrella to stay up.",
"",
"“Now, I am a big lady with a long skirt and I am going over to the store,” she said to
herself as she gathered her skirt up with one hand, and held the umbrella up straight
and fine with the other. Walking carefully, “because it is so muddy,” she said, and down
the street she started. Pretty soon a gust of the playful south wind came along and lifted
the umbrella right out of Marjorie’s little hand and took it out into the middle of the
street and set it down.",
"",
"Forgetting the rainy day, the long skirt, and the mud, off the curbing she jumped and
ran for the umbrella. She had almost grasped it again, when along came another gust of
wind, and down the street bumpity-bump went the big, open umbrella. Marjorie started
to run after it, but over and over it went so much faster than a little girl could run that it was soon far out of her reach.",
"",
"Then she began to cry.",
"“Catch it, oh, catch it!” she screamed, as she ran.",
"",
"The lady I told you about heard the cry, and looking up from her reading, saw the big
umbrella go rolling past, followed by the frightened, crying little girl. Down the steps she ran and out into the street after the umbrella. “Bump,” it went up against a telephone
pole, and the wind left it there. In a moment the lady had it in her hand.",
"",
"“I want it down, oh, please, I want it down,” sobbed Marjorie all out of breath.",
"",
"“Now, it’s all right. Don’t cry anymore,” said the lady as she put it down and handed it to
Marjorie, kissing her little tear-stained face."
"",
""Marjorie clung to it with both hands and started for home. She wanted to put the
umbrella back by the hall tree and tell mother all about the runaway."
"
]
,
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": "q1",
          "question": "Why did Marjorie pick up the umbrella?",
          "options": {
            "A": "She wanted to see how heavy it was.",
            "B": "She thought that it was going to rain.",
            "C": "She was trying to keep dry in the rain.",
            "D": "She wanted to pretend it was a rainy day."
          },
          "answer": "D"
        },
        {
          "id": "q2",
          "question": "Why did Marjorie start to cry?",
          "options": {
            "A": "She lost the umbrella.",
            "B": "She was blown by the wind.",
            "C": "She got stuck out in the rain.",
            "D": "She got her clothes all muddy."
          },
          "answer": "A"
        },
        {
          "id": "q3",
          "question": "Why did Marjorie jump off the curb?",
          "options": {
            "A": "She was trying to cross the street.",
            "B": "She was trying to get out of the rain.",
            "C": "She was trying to catch the umbrella.",
            "D": "She was trying to get out of the mud."
          },
          "answer": "C"
        },
        {
          "id": "q4",
          "question": "Why was the lady able to get the umbrella for Marjorie?",
          "options": {
            "A": "The wind stopped blowing it.",
            "B": "The wind had blown it into a tree.",
            "C": "The wind put it right into her hand.",
            "D": "The wind blew it against the telephone pole."
          },
          "answer": "D"
        },
        {
          "id": "q5",
          "question": "Why did Marjorie cling to the umbrella with both hands on her way home?",
          "options": {
            "A": "She wanted to get the umbrella to stay up.",
            "B": "She did not want the umbrella to blow away again.",
            "C": "She did not want her mother to know what had happened to the umbrella.",
            "D": "She wanted to hold the umbrella the same way she had seen the lady hold
it."
          },
          "answer": "B"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
